MAHMOUD HIJAZI

Fullertony, CA 92831

Phone: 949.378.6274 | Email: hijaziii@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: bit.ly/3nsjsFs | GitHub: github.com/hijaziii | Portfolio: hijaziii.github.io/Personal--Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Management and Economics. Recently finished a 24-week intensive program at UCLA to upskill as a Full Stack Web Developer and engaged in a multitude of projects acquiring practical experience in the field. Known among my class to be determined to excel at learning and applying technology to practical business use-cases.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

Frameworks: Node. js, Express.js, React.js, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Materialize

Databases & Tools: MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku, Git, OAuth, Postman

PROJECTS

KAMPers Visitors Management System | github.com/koyeary/hydrohomies |

kampers-vms.herokuapp.com

The KAMPers Visitor management system (VMS) helps manage and track visitors, allows selective access to buildings and improves the overall visitor experience. This web application allows customers to set up appointments and uses QR codes for verification. Also has a video chat feature for immediate building access.

- I developed the employee appointments admin page with full CRUD functionality"axios"; Backend interaction through api "Mongoose".
- I re-built the registration and login page using more modern technologies for better maintenance.
- I also helped code-review the video chat feature for the VMS.

Technologies Used:

HTML, Javascript, CSS, Bootstrap, NodeJS: "expressJS, MongoDB, React.js, Passport, Google OAuth, bcrypt, Mongoose (MERN), GitHub, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas via Heroku.

Lunde Water | github.com/hijaziii/hydrohomies | lunde-water.herokuapp.com

Lunde Water specializes in delivering state certified potable water to over 1000 customers. I worked on a team of 4 to develop an ecommerce and work-order platform which acts as a portal for customers to request water, with features like an automatic scheduling and payment system, a secure portal for administrators to view/revise worker schedules, a map of customers with info, and a portal for drivers to clock in/out and view info for jobs they are assigned.

• I have researched, designed and developed the customer payment portal using <u>Stripe's Payment API</u>.

Technologies Used:

HTML, Javascript, CSS, Materialize, NodeJS, ExpressJS, mySQL express-handlebars, passport, bcrypt, stripe, seguelize", Github, Heroku Cloud Hosting Platform, JawsDB via Heroku using mySQL.

California Parking Services | github.com/hijaziii/California-Parking-Services | hijaziii.github.io/California-Parking-Services

California Parking Services is a parking management company based in Commerce. They provide services throughout California. Their website shows customers all the services that they provide.

• I have worked on rebuilding their transportation and contact page and also worked with two third party API's, "Google Maps" and "Covid-19 tracker" on the home page.

Technologies Used:

HTML, Javascript, CSS, Materialize, Github.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer (Volunteer) American International University

07/2020 – Current Los Angeles, California

I started working with the American International University as a volunteer to continue to develop and progress my skills as a Full Stack Developer. I worked with a team of 3 to help develop a touchless visitor management system using the MERN stack.

Key Accomplishments:

The new system that I helped develop allows customers to custom schedule appointments either online or on-demand onsite using video conferencing. Customers with appointments receive customized QR codes upon approval via email which grants them access to the building. The system also integrates with Google oAuth services for ease of registration & access. Reminders delivered via SMS & email services.

Valet Manager California Parking Services

02/2009 - Current

Los Angeles, California

California Parking Services is a renowned valet parking agency used by major entertainment and sporting events throughout the Los Angeles area. My role as a supervisor of 20 consists of:

- Supervising attendants and coordinate operation of automobile storage garage and parking lot.
- Planning work schedules, assign duties and supervise workers' activities to ensure compliance with established rules and regulations.
- Maintaining a daily record of operations, including money received, services performed and accidents reported.

EDUCATION

UCLA Coding BootCamp: Los Angeles, CA

03/2020 - 09/2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

SUNY Empire State College: Saratoga Springs, NY

2003 - 2008 (Transitioned from American University of Science and Technology, Beirut, Lebanon)

Bachelor of Science - Business and Management Economics